London SE9 2PN, UK ☐ 07554 429 647
 ☐ www.linkedin.com/in/jagdeep-birdee
 Bē www.behance.net/jagdeepbirdee

About

UI/UX designer with previous experience in graphic design, illustration and online e-commerce businesses.

Applies graphic design principles to create visually stunning digital interfaces that elevate user experience and drive engagement.

Skills

Competitor Analysis
User research & Testing
Wireframing
Prototyping
Style Guide & Brand Guidelines
Responsive Design & Breakpoints
HTML & CSS

Tools

Figma
Adobe XD
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe After Effects
VisualStudio Code
Github

Recent UI/UX Projects

Liquid - UI/UX Budgeting App

Jan 2024 - Feb 2024

- 40+ screens finalised within timeframe.
- · Conducted UX research and virtual interviews to better understand needs of the user.
- Scenario-based user testing conducted on mid-fi wireframes.
- Complete Style Guide/Brand Guidelines created, along with a website landing page and the finished hi-fi prototype.

Matchpoint - UI/UX Tennis App

Sept 2023 - Dec 2023

- 2 finished prototypes of the app were developed for both iOS and Android.
- Competitor analysis and user personas helped to clarify user requirements for the app.
- Lo-fi and mid-fi wireframes were tested and iterated upon numerous times.
- Clarified where sounds and haptic feedback would be incorporated into the app.
- Style Guide created, including a custom icon set.

KitchenTime - UI/UX Responsive Recipe Web App

May 2023 - Sept 2023

- · Conducted in-depth competitor analysis to pinpoint strengths and weaknesses in overall app user experience.
- Interviewed 3 participants and synthesized findings to identify user cooking habits and needs.
- · Jobs To Be Done and MVP document was drafted to clarify essential app requirements.
- Multiple rounds of user testing was conducted, including a Preference Test on UsabilityHub and a Moderated Usability Test.
- The layout was adjusted at each breakpoint to ensure the design remained intact across all screen sizes.

Work Experience

Birdee Heating Ltd - Admin Assistant

Jul 2016 - Apr 2023

- Prepared and organised supplier invoices, statements, and delivery notes by month end, to ensure payments are logged correctly.
- · Stocktook on a weekly basis, to maintain correct stock levels for day-to-day operation of the business.
- · Received and checked deliveries for any discrepancies with the products ordered.
- · Generated pricelists using Microsoft Excel.

Online E-Commerce Store - Owner

Jun 2022 - Dec 2022

- · Conducted competitor analysis and product research to identify profitable niches.
- · Sourced products and negotiated with 3 overseas suppliers to ensure cost was within range.
- Ordered samples and tested products to ensure good quality.
- Built 2 branded online stores using Shopify and various plugins.
- Curated a successful marketing campaign and attained over 300,000 views across 3 social media channels.
- Successfully fulfilled and shipped products internationally.

Odeon - Cinema Host Nov 2018 - Aug 2019

- Provided seamless and high-quality customer service for 40 films over the course of 10 months.
- Coordinated and managed 18 screens simultaneously of which total capacity exceeds 2000 people, ensuring smooth changeovers between films.
- Promoted to the VIP Gallery Team (responsible for hosting events, parties, and providing a high-quality guest experience in the VIP lounge) after showcasing strong communication skills and work-ethic, which helped increase guest retention and positive reviews for the branch.
- Hosted 3 red-carpet Nollywood movie premieres, working together as part of the Gallery Team to set up music and catering.
- Trained 4 new employees, supervised their shifts, explained their duties, and answered any of their queries.

Education & Qualifications

CareerFoundry - UI Design course

Dec 2022 - Mar 2024

- Completed five UI/UX projects with working prototypes.
- Modules Included; Frontend Development for Designers, UX & UI design processes, Designing for iOS & Android, Responsive design.

Brainnest - Graphic Design in Industry Course

Feb 2023 - Mar 2023

- Four real-world projects completed within a deadline, including group work.
- Topics included; Designing for print mediums; Brand Identity Guidelines, Consumer Psychology, Industry practices.

Warwick Business School - BSc Accounting & Finance

Sept 2019 - Jun 2022

· Attained CertHE level.